<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>python on Gabe</title><link>https://gabriel.gaucimaistre.com/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in python on Gabe</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabriel.gaucimaistre.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Data Science &lt;3 Clean Code</title><link>https://gabriel.gaucimaistre.com/2021/05/data-science-3-clean-code/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabriel.gaucimaistre.com/2021/05/data-science-3-clean-code/</guid><description>DISCLAIMER
The following are simply my views and in no way reflect those of the whole industry.
I&amp;rsquo;m back with another controversial topic!
There is a common misconception among people with an academic background that being a Data Scientist means you do not need to care about writing good clean code, because you&amp;rsquo;re not a Software Developer or a Machine Learning Engineer. Data Science is all about running experiments on data and you should not need to spend your precious time worrying about making things look pretty.</description></item><item><title>I Don't Like Data Science Competitions</title><link>https://gabriel.gaucimaistre.com/2021/05/i-dont-like-data-science-competitions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabriel.gaucimaistre.com/2021/05/i-dont-like-data-science-competitions/</guid><description>DISCLAIMER
The following are simply my views and in no way reflect those of the whole industry.
What is a Data Science competition? Data Science competitions have become extremely popular in the past 5 years. They are not only popular on sites such as Kaggle[0], but also when interviewing with companies for a role on the job market in the form of a candidate test. These tests have quickly turned into a way to judge the performance of a participant/candidate&amp;rsquo;s submission and determine whether they have succeeded in the challenge or not.</description></item><item><title>10 Reasons Why You Should Learn Julia</title><link>https://gabriel.gaucimaistre.com/2018/09/10-reasons-why-you-should-learn-julia/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabriel.gaucimaistre.com/2018/09/10-reasons-why-you-should-learn-julia/</guid><description>Even though it has 1-based indexing.
What is Julia? Julia is a fairly modern language, developed in 2009 by Jeff Bezanson, Stefan Karpinski, Viral B. Shah, and Alan Edelman who had the idea of designing a language that was free, high-level, and fast. The language was officially unveiled to the world in 2012 when the team launched a website with a blog post explaining the language’s mission. When asked why they named the language “Julia”, Alan Edelman turned down the thought that it was named after the fractal, but claimed that it just came up in a random conversation years ago when someone suggested arbitrarily that “Julia” would be a good name for a programming language.</description></item></channel></rss>